但他是只蜗牛 懂吗 叫的时候却是"喵"
But it's a snail, you see, and it go--it go, "Meow."
- 他是什么 怎么叫 - 喵喵叫
- It's a what, now? What? - It meows.
接着他在海绵宝宝肚子上爬来爬去 就像他宠物什么的
Then it ooze all up SpongeBob's belly Iike it's his pet and shit.
你们几个动画看太多了
Yo, y'all niggers watch too many cartoons, I swear.
Pandemic
看见没 这就是司法体系的症结所在
Hey! Look, see, this is what's wrong with the justice system right here.
人被关进去却待不长
Niggers get locked up and they don't stay that way.
让人很难严肃对待这体系啊
They make it hard to take this shit serious.
- 怎么 你告密了咋地 - 靠 没有
- What, you snitchin' or something? - Shit no, man.
你知道他们只让我服了4个月 对吧
You know they only gave me, like, four, right?
知道我怎么说吗 我愿服完15个月
Know what I'm saying? I done 15 months.
能出来快活 我就想 "管他呢"
So with good time, I'm like, "Man, what the fuck?"
- 靠 - 就是这样 伙计
- Shit. - Yeah, man.
那...
So...
今时不同往日了 但会好起来的
Yeah, man, it ain't like it was, but it'll do.
现在我们是替谁卖
So who we slinging for?
- Marlo Stanfield 嗯 知道 - 拜托 伙计
- Marlo Stanfield. Yo, man, yeah. - Come on, man!
我从Slim Charles那弄了不少好货 但...
I was getting this nice package from Slim Charles, but...
Marlo有帮打手压制着我们 只好这样
Marlo got the muscle to hold us down, so that's where we at.
靠 哪个大哥都一样
Shit, one boss same as the next, man.
看着别让他们睡着了 好吗
Make sure they ain't sleepin', all right?
嘿 小Kev
Hey, yo, Little Kev,
我跟你提起过他 Poot 对吧
I told you about the boy, Poot, right?
嗯 萝莉杀手
- Yeah. Pussy hound.
- 刚出来? 关多久 - 15个月
- You just home? How long in? - 15 months.
- 出来玩过女人了吗 - 靠 我觉得我已经中招了
- You got laid yet? - Shit, I think I already been burnt.
靠 今天得让谁载我去趟诊所
- Shit, I might need a ride to the clinic today. - ??
我发现这地方一点没变嘛
I see ain't shit changed around this joint.
靠墙站着 同志们
On the wall, gents.
大家行个方便 你们谁是小Kevin?
Make this easy on all of us. Which one of youse is Little Kevin?
拜托 伙计们 没啥大不了的
Come on, fellas. It ain't no big deal.
我们只是要跟那混小子聊聊
We just need some face time with the motherfucker.
你叫Kevin?
Your name Kevin?
- 不 这位是... - Poot 我叫Poot
No, this is, uh-- Poot. I'm Poot, yo.
Poot 对哦 你不是被关了还是中枪了吗
Poot, right, yeah. Didn't you get locked up or shot or something?
假释委员会认为该再给我一次机会
Society say l deserve another chance.
是吗 走着瞧吧 这里哪个傻帽是小Kevin?
Yeah? Let's see. Which one of these dickheads here is Little Kevin?
- 伙计 我不认识什么Kevin - 真该让假释委员会啃我鸡巴了
- Man, I don't know no Kevin. - Society can bite my dick.
拜托 Bodie 我知道这孩子跟你混
Come on, Bodie. I know this kid works up here with you.
- 你叫什么名字 - 你看我很小吗
- What's your name? - Do I look little to you?
好吧 去他的 体重小于150磅或矮于5尺6的都给我上车
All right. Fuck this. Everyone under 150 lbs or 5'6" is in the cab.
你 你 还有你
You, you, and you.
除非你们出生证明是不是这么写的 你们就是我的小Kevin们
And unless I see birth certificates saying otherwise, you're my Little Kevins.
如果这样还找不到 我们还会再来 懂吗
And if that don't get it, we're coming the fuck back. ??
你在假释吗
You got any paper on you?
我知道个屁
Man, fuck if I know.
这些警察要是知道哪怕稍微查查
These police out here knew how to flip it even just a little,
我就该戴着手铐了 知道吗
my shit would be in handcuffs. You know?
不专业啊
They don't know shit.
靠
Damn!
火线重案组 第四季 第9集
the.wire.s04e09
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
你也可以丢了买台新的 - Proposition Joe
Harford郡 拘留中心 Bel Air 马里兰州
你做我司机?
You my ride?
我他妈来做你救星
I'm your motherfucking savior, is what I am.
早告诉过你Andre是在陷害我
Told y'all Andre was lying on me, yo.
我不是为你这么做的
I didn't do it for you.
事实上...
Fact is...
如果我能把我结了的案子再翻出来
if I could work back on whatever cases I already caught,
你立马就得滚进去
you might be going right back inside.
知道
I know.
- 所以是谁杀了那个跑腿妹 - 不知道
- So who did kill that delivery girl? - I don't know.
我知道不是Andre 他没那么冷血
Know it wasn't Andre. His blood don't run that kind of cold.
他从谁那儿拿货
Who he getting his package from?
我可以再去那个藏毒点吓吓他们
Saying I could go back to the crib and bear up,
打探一下 如果你愿意的话
find some things out for you if you want me to--
- 你欠我的 混球 - 我知道我该怎么做 伙计
- You owe me, motherfucker. - I'm saying I knowa I do, man.
如果你想还我 知道该怎么做吗
And if you want to pay down any part of this debt, you know what you gotta do for me?
不许再杀人
No more bodies.
别再背上人命
No more fucking bodies from you.
别再反击 别再报复
No more comebacks or get-evens on this.
别再杀戮
No more killing.
你欠我一句话
You owe me your word.
好吧 伙计 我不杀人
All right, man. No bodies on me.
真想让我放心 就让我载你去Aberdeen火车站
You really want to ease my mind, you'll let me drive you down to Aberdeen rail station,
- 把你送上北行的列车 - 不行 伙计
- put you on a northbound train. - Naw, man.
我就熟巴尔的摩
Baltimore's all I know.
你知道家的感觉的
You know what it is like, homey.
人总得活在自己熟悉的地方 对吧
Man gotta live what he know, right?
你说得很对 有很多重要因素需要考虑
You're absolutely right. There are many significant factors to consider,
但控制犯罪
but getting crime under control is
是激励投资 起动经济增长的关键
key to sparking investment here, jump-starting growth.
如果你能保证安全 就会有投资
If you make it safe, they will come.
我不想以伸手要钱来开始我们美好的关系
Well, I hate to begin our beautiful relationship with my hand out,
但据说我办公室的两项联邦拨款今年黄了
but I'm told that two federal grants to my office dry up this year.
没错 年初的时候
That's right. Come the first of the year,
这笔司法部拨款就没影儿了 而你还有12个公诉人要养活
those DOJ grants evaporate, and you're out 12 prosecutors.
我还指着你能用普通基金资助一下
Well, I was hoping you'd be able to absorb that in the general fund,
也许还能多给点
maybe even throw in a little bit more,
好跟警局和检察长有得一拼
make it competitive with the PD and Attorney General's jobs--
加入点新鲜血液 现在这样我们快挂了
starts the turnover. It's killing us.
那现在正是时候 我是说 今年收入超过预期
This would be the time to do it. I mean, we're over the revenue expected
财政年正赶上房地产市场火爆
for this point in the fiscal year next to the real estate market.
超了多少 因为我想立即
How much past? 'Cause l want to come out of the box
给警察大幅加薪 尤其是局长的薪水
with a big bump in police salaries, in particular the commissioner's salary,
要涨大概5万
which needs to jump, like, 50 grand.
乐观估计大概一次性盈余两千万
Well, a good guess would be a one-shot surplus of about 20 million.
但那是应急储备 不能光用在打击犯罪上
But that's rainy-day money for more than crime.
北大街那边传言学校都在亏损
Word around North Avenue is that the schools are running a deficit.
不好意思 你刚刚是说 给Ervin Burrell加薪5万?
Excuse me. Did you say a 50,000 bump for Ervin Burrell?
准确的说不是给Burrell的
Well, no, not for Burrell per se.
那就是给下任局长咯
Oh, for the next police commissioner, then.
- 你是这个意思吗 - 考虑到将来 这是有道理的
- That's what you mean? - Well, looking ahead, it makes sense.
炒了Burrell会让我一大票选民不安
Because firing Burrell would upset a good-sized block of my constituency,
更别提部长们了
not to mention the ministers.
我想预算主席也会为
And I think the budget chair might have a difficult time
批准这么高的薪水辗转不安吧
allowing a higher salary to be approved.
事实上 我可以保证 如果这个提议进入预算
In fact, I can guarantee if that proposal's in the budget--
你记住 你的首个议案
your first, for the record--
就没法完整地被委员会通过
the bill won't come out of committee intact.
我只是说 最终Burrell局长会离职
I'm just saying that in the event Commissioner Burrell were to leave,
我们想涨薪以吸引最好的继任者
we'd want to bump that salary in order to attract the best candidates,
特别是国内最优秀的非裔美国人
in particular the best African-American candidates from across the nation.
他任期还有三年 怎么会离职
With three years left in his term, why would he leave?
议员 公共安全委员会的情况 你可能还不太了解
Councilman, what may not have been obvious to you on the Public Safety Subcommittee
预算程序是个小心谨慎 精心安排的过程
is that the budget process is a carefully orchestrated ballet,
是政府各机关通力合作的成果
a cooperative effort between the branches of government.
主席女士 这一通力合作成功的细微差别
Well, Madam President, the nuances of that cooperative effort
我渐渐开始明白了
are beginning to come into focus for me.
谢谢你 主席女士
Thank you, Madam President.
进来吧 各位 别在门边站着
Come on in, everyone. Don't wait by the door.
Duquan 你坐这
Duquan, you're here.
Randy 你坐这 不 你俩换个位
Randy, you're here. No, you two switch.
Calvin 你坐前排
Calvin, you're here in the front.
Quenice 你坐这 Michael 你坐这
Quenice, you're here. Michael, you're here.
Destiny 这儿 Myesha 这儿
Destiny, here. Myesha, here.
Dashonda 这儿
Dashonda, here.
快 进来 别在门边站着
Come on, keep moving. Don't stop at the door.
进来 开始上课了
Come in. Let's get started.
可能会有麻烦
Could be a problem.
为什么
How so?
重案组盯上你的人了
Your boy been assigned to what they call the Major Crimes Unit.
什么意思
Meaning what?
那帮混球之前搞了三次市级的窃听
They the motherfuckers that did the last three city wiretaps--
一次窃听了Barksdale的办公室
one where they bugged Barksdale's office,
一次在Park Heights窃听了Kentel
another where they hit Kentel up in Park Heights.
最近一次 靠
And the last one-- shit.
Stringer Bell的电话被他们听了个遍
They was all up on Stringer Bell's cell phone.
你不是还在用即弃型手机吧
You ain't still using burners, is you?
我每两周扔一次
I'm dumping them every two weeks.
还不够
Not good enough.
看看吧
You read that.
你会发现Stringer每天换个号码
You'll see that Stringer was changing his number every damn day
他们还是从个该死的手机信号塔中 提取出了他的声音
and they still pulled the motherfucker's voice off a goddamn cell phone tower.
市警干的?
City police did that?
(Stringer的信息)
- 你从哪弄来的 - 法院书记员办公室
- Where'd you get this? - Courthouse clerk's office.
他们起诉完后这东西就会向公众公开
Hey, the shit's open to the public after they finish prosecuting your ass.
你得放弃手机 孩子
You need to lose them cell phones, son.
至于我
Me--
我一年内都不碰手机
I ain't as so much as touched a burner in a year.
- 5尺9又8分之3寸 - 没错
- 5'9" and 3/8? - You got it.
现在拿着尺子 张开双臂
Now, hold the measure and spread your arms out to the side.
干什么呢
What you got?
我也想要
I want one.
给你的猫吃吗
So, your cat can eat 'em?
你怎么找到的
So, how'd you find them?
我去用计算器
I'm going to the calculators.
给我
Give me that.
- 给我 - 一样长
- Give it here. - The same.
你身高和臂展等长
Your height and your arm span-- identical.
Quenice?
看吧 你要害我被骂了
See, look. You about to get me in trouble.
你说你喜欢拳击 对吧
So, you say you like to box, right?
你会有不错的成绩哦
You must have some kind of reach.
只要你知道上哪找 电脑上的东西都很便宜
Everything cheap on computers if you know where to look for it.
就是说我从韩国人那拿货的价
Yo, this mean the price I'm getting from the Koreans,
还是有水分
yo, they still marking it up some.
肯定是这样 我用这个能赚上两倍
They gotta be. I can make twice as much using this here.
不成
Uh-uh.
没戏
Can't.
沿低Patapsco Westport区域 所有这些地段可以改建了
All this along the lower Patapsco Westport area is ready for a turn.
临近市中心地区和巴-华干道
The proximity to downtown and the B.W. Parkway
专为去华盛顿上班的人而设
make it ideal for Washington commuters.
- 规划是这样的 - 有什么能加速经济增长的吗
- That's a given. - Anything to speed it up?
港口步道就可以 从桥的两端向西延伸
A harbor promenade could work, going west from both sides of the bridge.
南港步道
The South Harbor Promenade, brought to you by--
- 由Thomas Carcetti市长 - 巴尔的摩市民为您呈现
- Mayor Thomas Carcetti-- - and the citizens of Baltimore.
跟建体育馆和扩建水族馆 不在一个档次上 不是吗
Doesn't quite have the same ring as a stadium or an aquarium expansion, does it?
- 这是个开始 - 再往东 就是Locust Point水产口岸
It's a start. Further east, you've got the Locust Point Marine Terminal,
很不幸 那里还在运营
which, unfortunately, is still a working enterprise,
越接近Brooklyn/Curtis湾
and the further you go into Brooklyn/Curtis Bay,
地平线就越被遮挡
the more the skyline disappears.
这样我们就损失了华盛顿的居民
We lose the Washington crowd.
那部分滨水地区需要不同的规划
For that part of the waterfront, you're gonna need a different draw.
- 赌场? - 城市规划默认项?
- Casinos? - Oh, the urban planning default?
我可不想见到随之而来的犯罪
I don't want to see the kind of crime that comes with casinos.
- 税基毕竟是税基 - 这样我可不干了
- Tax base is tax base. - This is where I get off the boat.
为了税基出卖滨水区是一回事
It's one thing to sell waterfront for tax base,
想赚我社区的钱又是另一回事了
but now you're just sucking paychecks out of my community.
这只是个想法 无论如何
Well, it was just a thought. And, anyway,
我们讨论过头了
we're getting ahead of ourselves.
这只是为数众多的漫长会议中的第一次
This is just the first long meeting of many.
感谢各位 我们稍后继续
So, thanks to everyone, and we'll continue this later.
主席女士 跟你聊聊好吗
Madam President, a word with you?
有空吗
Do you have a minute?
你我这就有分歧了?
You and me, we got a problem already?
只是想帮你搞清楚程序 选上的...
Just trying to help guide you through the process, Mr. Mayor...
...市长先生
...Elect.
感觉更像是你把我拖过雷区 Nerese
Felt more like you were dragging me across a minefield, Nerese.
- 你为什么这么恼我 - 听着
- Why you so pissed off at me? - Look.
Clarence本来不论什么原因都不会再参选
Clarence shouldn't have run again for any number of reasons.
我已经准备好上位了
I was ready to step up,
这是早就谈好的交易 时机一到他就会支持我
and the deal was cut long ago that he'd back me when the time came.
你和Tony...
You and Tony--
你们插队了 本来还没轮到你们
you guys jumped the line. It wasn't your turn.
哇哦 哇哦
Oh, whoa. Whoa.
首先 我很抱歉 如果Tony和我毁了你的庆功宴
First of all, I'm sorry if Tony and I ruined your party plans,
但我对你和Clarence的小灶毫不知情
but I wasn't privy to whatever you and Clarence cooked up.
撇开这些不谈 我还期望我们能亲密合作呢
That aside, I was kind of looking forward to working closely together.
我想我们能成一番大事
I think that we could make things happen.
你只有一届任期 Tommy
You're only getting the one term, Tommy.
下届我可不会避战
I'm not gonna stand down next time.
你凭什么认为我会待那么久
What makes you think I'll even be around that long?
州长竞选两年内就要开始了 计划是可以变动的
Governor's race is in two years, and plans can change.
你可能会发现到2008年 连竞选演讲都不用说 你已经是市长了
You might find yourself mayor in 2008 without so much as a campaign speech.
要找你还真不容易
Wasn't easy tracking you down.
你原来给我的号码都不用了
The numbers I got for you don't work no more.
看来你有麻烦了
I see you got a problem.
看着挺惨啊 Bubs
Looking rough, Bubs.
我一直想把自己洗白 你知道的...
I been keeping it clean, you know...
只推着我的小货车
pushing my carts and all.
但有个年轻人
But this one young man--
每次碰上我 就把我抢个清光
every time I cross him, I get tossed for what I got on me.
现金 毒品
Cash, pills.
我发誓 他完全把我当提款机了
I mean, he look on me like an ATM or some shit, I swear.
我可以帮你干活 Kima
I'm ready to work, Kima.
让那混球离我远点 我愿替你做牛做马
Get this motherfucker off me, I'll do what you need.
看着我 Bubs 我现在不在缉毒科了
Look at me, Bubs. I ain't in Narco.
懂了 你看上去不错
Yeah, I see. You look nice.
我现在在凶杀科干
I'm working homicides.
这么说 如果那坏小子把我杀了 你就能帮上忙了 对吧
So, if the bad boy happen to kill me, you can help me out then, right?
如果我们开车在这转转 你把那混球指给我看吗
If we drive around a bit, you think you can put eyes on this motherfucker?
试试吧
I can try.
这么说 Nerese已经在找茬了
So, Nerese is bucking already.
看样子如果Royce坐不上市长的位子 就该她来坐了
Feels like if the mayor's chair ain't gonna go to Royce, it should be hers.
问题是她会把任何一项为局长加薪的提议
Problem is she's gonna see any proposal to raise the commissioner's salary
视为针对Burrell的行动
as a move against Burrell.
本来就是啊
Which it is.
不能加薪 就不能吸引强势的少数派继任者
We can't raise the salary, we can't attract strong minority candidates.
没有强势的继任者 就会甩不掉手上的人
No strong candidates, we can't get rid of the guy we got.
要容忍Burrell当局长真是操蛋
Fuck if I'm gonna live with Burrell as my commissioner.
- 要是他退出呢 - 退出?
- What if he quits? - Quits?
也许他感到羞愧 如果他依自己意愿退出
Maybe the man can be shamed. If he leaves on his own account,
我们就不会惹到Nerese和部长们了
that takes us off the hook with Nerese and the ministers, right?
不 我是说 我们不是要你的信用卡号
No. I mean, we don't want your credit card number.
我们甚至不用知道卡号
I mean, we won't even know the number.
我们只要你买下糖果
We just need you to order the candy.
而你付得起现金?
And you have cash up front?
他可以还你 P先生 等他卖完后
He pay you back, Mr. P. When he sell off, man,
- 他会还你的 - 是啊
- he gonna pay you back. - Yeah.
分红
Points on the package, huh
- 不行 - 拜托啦 Pryzbo先生
- No way. - Aw, come on, Mr. Pryzbo.
这不是能让我们学好数学么? 加 减
I mean, doesn't it teach us math? Addition, subtraction, uh,
四分之一 四分之一块 一毛 十分之一?
a quarter, a quarter of a dollar, a dime, a tenth, you know?
没现金 就不能用卡
No cash, no card.
好吧
All right. Fine.
先给钱
Cash up front.
没问题
No problem.
如果你明天掏出一把钞票 Randy
And if you come in with a wad of bills tomorrow, Randy,
得让我知道是哪来的
I want to know where they came from.
我不想你们在街角混
I don't want either of you out on the corner.
行
All right.
Thiessen女士 没事吧
Ms. Thiessen, you okay?
我想我车被偷了
I think my car's been stolen.
伙计 好吧... 我的意思是
Yeah, man. All right...so what I'm saying is
你从那儿的Bentlow那拿货 给那边的Rosewood
that you got from Bentlow down there to Rosewood right here.
懂吗 现在我管着从Monroe直到Pacer的街角
All right? Now, I got the block from Monroe all the way down to Pacer,
所以从那边开始都要你来负责
so I got you covered from that side,
不过你要在Franklintown安排些望风的 注意从另一边来的人
but you gotta put lookouts in Franklintown to catch anybody coming from the other way.
- 好的 明白了 - 准备好干活了吗
- All right, I got you. - Are you ready to work?
嗯 给我货源 就可以开干了
Yeah, just get my re-up. We'll go on about the shit for real.
- 不 你准备好了吗 - 准备好了
- No, are you ready to work? - Yeah. Ready to work.
- Donut 替我传话给小Kevin - 好的
- Donut, go talk to Little Kevin for me. - All right.
- 看着车 - 你听着
- Watch the ride. - Hey, yo, look.
伙计 千万别再让你妈来替你说话了
Man, please do not be having your mama come talk for you.
伙计 我没让她来
Man, I ain't have her do nothing.
她就这么过来了
She just get on her horse and come with it.
听着 我现在可不想再事无巨细 帮你和你家人了...
Look. I done did everything I can for you and yours,but...
从现在开始 你妈妈们就帮不了你了 懂吗
from here on, your moms can't do nothing to help. All right?
他?
Him
Wee-Bey生的?
From Wee-Bey?
你几个妈啊?
Your moms?
没见到混蛋Andre
No sign of the motherfucker Andre.
店关了一周了
Store been padlocked a week.
也没见他打电话要货
Ain't even calling for his re-up.
监狱里那小子怎样了
Check the man at the jail?
传言Omar两周没出现了
Yeah. People say Omar ain't even been on the tier for two weeks,
他要么待在哪 要么被关郡里了
so he either staying someplace or they got him at county lock-up.
又或者诉讼撤销了
Or the charges been dropped.
如果那兔爷突然现身 他又会重操旧业
If this cocksucker's sprung, my man is backing up on his story.
就是说他会找上你们
Mean he could back up on y'all.
我盯着
I'm on it.
纽约小子们怎么样了
How about the New York boys?
干掉了五个 其他都躲起来了
We dropped five of them. The rest went to ground.
开车穿越东巴尔的摩 连个戴洋基帽子的人都看不到
Drive through East Baltimore, you don't even see a Baltimore nigger with a Yankee cap.
这边也要继续盯着吗
Want us to stay on that, too?
我跟那肥佬谈过了
I talked to the fat man,
到此为止了
but I think we're done there.
Andre那破事 首要任务
This shit with Andre-- job one.
没有 我们可以再试试大街那边
No. We could try the avenue again.
他有时在市集后面
He be behind the market sometimes.
听着 Bubs 我可没一整天陪你
Look, Bubs, I ain't got all fucking day.
我当班 要查谋杀案
I'm on shift work now. I'm working murders.
他这周抢了我四次 Kima
He banked me four times this week, Kima.
我连做梦都要梦到那个没教养的混球了
I'm having dreams about this low-bottom motherfucker.
好吧 这样吧 你想要工作?
All right.I tell you what-- you want to work?
我会告诉重案组的Sydnor或Herc
I'll call Sydnor or Herc down at Major Crimes,
让你跟着某人查毒品
put you with someone doing drug work.
你为他们做事 他们会帮你的 行吗
You work for them, they'll help you with your problem.All right?
- 我现在就要帮助 Kima 女人啊... - 我会告诉他们的
- I need this now, Kima. Woman-- - I'll tell them that.
告诉我你住哪
So show me where you're living,
我让他们去找你
and I'll tell them where they can find you.
左转
Make the left.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你告诉他 你不会杀人了
You told the man you not gonna kill no one.
我答应他的
I gave my word on that.
那我们来这干嘛 老爸
Fuck we doing back here then, Papa?
我还是可以拿枪指着Andre的脸 对吧
I can still put a gun in Andre's face, right?
他得跟我做些解释
That man got some explaining to do.
这边是死路了
It's dead out here, yo.
出去吧
Tip on out.
我不明白为什么他不相信我们
I don't know why he don't trust us with it, yo.
我是说 我们值得信任 不是吗
I mean, we trustworthy, ain't we?
只要筹齐第一笔订单的钱 就好办了
Just gotta get enough for the first order. Then we're good.
好 双六!
All right! Hard six!
再来 Trey!
Come on, trey!
我也来
I'm in.
走开 小鬼
Go away, boy.
- 你要玩? - 对
- Oh, you in? - Yeah.
赌过线
Pass line for me, yo.
该死
Oh, shit!
收钱吧 收钱吧 小鬼
Yeah. Get that money. Get that money, shorty.
收钱
Get that money.
我听说了 但一直不相信
I heard tell of it, but I didn't believe it.
这么多加班费 只是两个助办的案子
All this overtime, all for two cases as a secondary.
名字先是红的
First the names are red,
颜色表示案件侦破进度 黑色即结案
接着绿了 接着黑了
then they're green, then they're black.
这还不包括案子上庭 法庭支付给你的
And that doesn't even include the court pay you make if the soft case goes to trial.
- 真好 - 你准备用那笔钱干什么 Greggs警探?
- Sweet. - So, what you gonna do with yours, Detective Greggs, huh?
还债
Pay down some debt.
- 你走什么 - 你可是大杀四方啊
- Why you leaving? - Your luck ain't gonna change.
别担心 伙计
Don't worry about that, man.
谢谢你陪我们走 我还怕会被打劫呢
Yo, thanks for walking us off. I thought we was gonna get banked.
你不会打劫我们吧
You ain't gonna bank us, is you?
靠 你们觉得我就那么不感恩吗
Shit, boy. You think I'm that ungrateful?
我跟着你赌个10轮 比我一个月赢的还多
I followed you through 10 shooters and made more money that I have in a month.
我不会抢你们的
Nah. I ain't gonna rob you.
我只想知道你们下次什么时候 来玩骰子 懂吗
I just need to know next time you fade a dice game. You feel?
我是说 这就是数学了 概率之类的
I mean, it's all about the math, you know, the probabilities and all.
以前从没见你赌过
I ain't never seen you in a game before.
你上哪学来的
Where you learn your game?
Edward Tilghman中学
Edward Tilghman Middle.
靠
Shit.
我们的线索只有小Kevin
All we got is Little Kevin.
Bodie的小弟?
Oh, Bodie's boy, huh?
我说什么来着 Bubs消息灵通 来
What'd I tell you? Bubs gets it the first time. Here.
明天中午碰头 学校放学后
Y'all meet up with me in the afternoon tomorrow-- after school lets out--
我会给Kevin一顶新帽子
and I'll give Kevin a new hat.
帽子把戏? 不错
A hat trick? Cool.
- Herc 伙计? - 怎么
- Yo, Herc, man? - What's up?
这次我可不是为了钱
It's not about the money this time.
每天我不给他点什么 他就找我麻烦
He breaking me every day unless I give him something.
我 我受不了了 伙计
I can't-- I can't take it anymore, man.
我们搞定Kevin后 你去找那混蛋
Once we're done with Kevin, you go find this asshole,
打我手机
hit my cell phone.
我五分钟后就会出现在他面前
I'll be on him five minutes later.
我保证
I promise.
接着你倒进这个 看它嘶嘶响
Then you add this, yo, and watch it fizzle.
哇哦 哇哦 别倒那么多 别那么多
Whoa whoa whoa whoa. Not so much. Not so much.
这样会溢得到处都是的
You gonna make it spill everywhere, you see?
你怎么还上这来 这里不欢迎你
What are you still doing here? Ain't nobody want you here.
- 你妈欢迎我 - 是啊 你和你老二
- Your mama want me. - Yeah. You and the pipe.
你不该这样说你妈 Michael
Shouldn't talk about your mama like that, Michael.
爸 看见我的火山了吗
Hey, Daddy, see my volcano?
- Bug 上楼去 - 哦
- Bug, go upstairs. - okey
Bug也需要我
Bug need me, too.
周六 对吧
Saturday, right?
Bug需要我
Bug need me.
老师说我要戴眼镜
My teachers say I gotta need glasses.
需要个大人陪我
I gotta have an adult with me.
选眼镜 买单
Pick 'em up. Sign for 'em.
Bug 回你楼上房间
Bug, go upstairs to your room.
冷漠啊 小鬼 你算什么
Ice cold, boy. Where you be?
你的灵魂得不到宽恕的
Ain't got a forgiveness to your soul.
- 去你的 - 注意用词
- Man, fuck you. - Watch your mouth.
你长大了 但还不够大
You're big, but not big enough.
现在...
Now...
税卡在哪 你妈说要给我
where's that D.S.S. card? Your mama said that come to me.
反正这月也不会剩什么钱
Ain't nothing left on this month's check anyway.
那就下月初前给我
Before the first of the month, then.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
进来吧
Uh, come on in.
看来小鬼把起居室都占了啊
I see the little man done took over the living room.
- 不错嘛 - 你知道的啦
- Good for him. - Well, you know how it goes.
开玩笑的
Well, I'm just messing with you.
地方不错 玩具也很合
Place looks great. Even the toys look like they belong.
- 这是... - 这个月和前两个月的
- This is... - this month and two going back.
我只是想把钱补上
I'm just trying to catch up.
感谢你没追着我要
I appreciate you not coming after me for it.
洗劫了个酒厂?
Knocking over liquor stores now?
凶杀科的加班费
Overtime from Homicide.
保持这水平 我付我那份就不成问题了
It stays like this, and I won't have a problem coming up with my share.
- Kima - 我不是"求你再接受我"
- Kima-- - this ain't, "Please take me back,"
但说好的嘛 对吧
but a deal's a deal, right?
我回来了
Hey, I'm home.
嘿 Elijah
Hey, Elijah.
嘿
Hey.
Kima 这位是Nancine Owens
Kima, this is Nancine Owens.
抱歉 地方很乱
Sorry. The place is a mess.
你可以留下来吃个饭 不过...
You could stay for dinner, but...
今晚我们还有客人
tonight we have people coming over.
事实上 算个庆祝会吧
It's a kind of a celebration, actually.
- 哦? - 我这周过了律师考试
- Yeah? - I passed the bar this week.
恭喜
Huh. Congratulations.
我工作上的那些女孩都有这问题
Most of the gals I work with have a problem with that.
- 什么问题 - 逃不出牢笼（跟过律师考试说法一致)
- With what? - Passing the bar.
我想我还是走吧
Well, guess I better be going.
谢谢你过来
Thanks for coming past.
- 我们铺个床... - 对
- Let's make bed... - Yeah.
很高兴认识你
Nice meeting you.
- Elijah? - 啊?
- Elijah? - Huh?
- 跟Kima阿姨说再见 - 再见
- Say bye to Aunt Kima. - Bye.
- Dre在哪 - 我不知道
- Where's Dre? - I don't know!
- 你信吗 - 不信
- You believe her? - No.
最后问你一次 Andre在哪
One last time. Where's Andre?
他说如果告诉我他在哪
He-- he said if he told me where he was going,
我会告诉你的
I'd have to tell you.
我不知道 不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
这回信了吗
You believe her now?
信了
Yeah.
靠 这么早当然安静啦
Dang. Sure is quiet this early.
你跟我去见P先生吗
Yo, you gonna come with me to see Mr. P?
不 你去吧 教室见
No, go on up. I'll see you in homeroom.
好
All right.
P先生
Mr. P.
Randy
Randy.
- Randy 你怎么... - 六比四或五大
- Randy, how did you-- - six beats four or five.
大部分时间八比十好 对吧
And most times eight is better than 10. Right?
你教导有方啊
You schooled me good.
- 你赌钱赢来的? - 我骰子也没碰
- You gambled for this? - I didn't even Pick up the dice.
我就是在那说 "过线 不过线"
I was all, "Pass, no pass."
那里有群人还跟着我下注呢
Got to the point where some of them was following me in there.
- 你不该赌博的 - 我知道
- You shouldn't gamble. - I know,
但我是说 比赛没问题 P先生
but I'm just saying, the math be right, Mr. P.
我午饭再回来 我们网购糖果 行吗
But I'm gonna come back at lunch, and we can computer up that candy, all right?
拜啦
Peace.
辞职?
Resign?
要么这样 要么局里的日常指挥
Either that or the day-to-day running of the department falls
移交给副局长
to the Deputy Commissioner for Operations.
Erv 我不隐瞒我想要改变
Erv, I have made no secret of wanting to make changes.
这么说Bill Rawls现在是改革的呼声了?
Oh, so Bill Rawls is now the voice of reform, is he?
这跟Rawls无关
This isn't about Rawls.
就近来发生的事 我不相信你
I have no faith in you, given recent events.
记得一年前我俩站在一个电话亭前
I know you remember the two of us sitting in this same booth a year ago,
你告诉我说你尊重指挥链
you telling me about how you respect the chain of command.
现在尊重吧
Well, respect it now.
每个部门的头头都乐意为市长效劳
Every department head serves at the pleasure of the mayor.
所以如果你炒了我 市长先生
So, if you're firing me, Mr. Mayor,
你要知道 我会安静地离开
I want you to know I will go quietly.
你会提交辞职信吗
You'll tender your letter of resignation?
不
Oh, no.
我不会主动辞职
I'm not offering to resign.
你想要我离职 就炒了我
If you want me to go, you're gonna have to shitcan me.
我知道有点小区别 不过...
A small distinction, I know, but...
同时
in the meantime,
既然你让Bill Rawls替我干我的活
since you have Bill Rawls doing my job for me,
今天又是个待在户外的好天气
and it's such a nice day out,
我想我就去森林公园狩猎吧
I think I'll go to Forest Park and shoot nine.
我想这次就你买单吧
The check is yours, I think.
选一桌 随便选
Pick a table, any table.
埃菲尔铁塔 大本钟 帝国大厦
Eiffel Tower, Big Ben, Empire State Building.
坐同一桌的是一个团队
Your table is your team.
先搭好模型的队赢
The team that puts its model together first wins.
你们说你们在街角能合作
Now, you say y'all can work together out on the corner.
- 我们就看看你们做这个能合作吗 - 什么奖励
- Let's see how you do on this. - Wins what?
金色大五角星什么的吧
Big fat gold stars and some shit.
到市里吃晚餐 餐厅随便选
Dinner downtown. Any restaurant you can agree on.
既然你们只对熟悉的东西感兴趣
Since y'all only seem willing to be interested in stuff you know,
我们原来是要找些更巴尔的摩的东西
we looked for things more like Baltimore.
Fayette街藏毒点的模型已经卖光了
The scale model of the Fayette Street stash house was all sold out.
你们只好将就了
So, y'all just gonna have to make do.
Colvin先生 盒子上说里面该有说明书的
Hey, um, Mr. Colvin, the box say there's supposed to be some instructions.
我们收走了 这样更好玩 你不觉得吗
We took those out. Makes it more interesting, don't you think?
就像我们在别的地方也不遵照指示 对吧
Yeah, it ain't like we follow instructions anywhere else, right?
我本来不想投诉的
And I ain't even want to put no charges on no more.
但你看 他们逼我的
But see, they made me do that,
现在他们要拿我出气了 因为事儿没成
and now they're gonna be mad at me 'cause it ain't stick.
"他们"是谁
Who be "they"?
我拿货的人
People I'm getting the package from.
我问你是谁
I'm asking who.
叫Marlo的家伙
Boy named Marlo.
他是西区老大 你听说过他?
He's big on the West Side. You heard of him?
有点印象
Vaguely recall the name.
所以他们忘记前 我得躲一段时间
So, I just need to chill for a while till they remember how to forget.
所以你来东区 期望我能把你藏起来
So, now you come over East Side and expect me to hide you.
为什么每个东区的黑鬼都觉得
Why is it that every Baltimore nigger think
跑路就是跨过市区呢
that running the fuck away means crossing downtown?
靠 你该跑去纽约或费城什么的地方
Shit, you ought to be in New York or Philly or some shit.
我知道 只是出了巴尔的摩我谁都不认识
No, see, I know that. It's just that I don't know no one outside of B'more.
我只是希望 用我的店交换  你也许可以...
And I was just hoping, let's say, trade out my store, you could maybe...you know..
给我些钱 找人送我出城
front me some cash, get me out of town with people you know.
我是说 我不想跑来东区找你
I mean, I'd come to the East Side to you,
但西区有太多Marlo的人了
but too many West Side motherfuckers are with Marlo.
你知道这些机器有什么问题吗
You know what the problem with these here machines?
他们太廉价了
They too cheap to begin with.
有人会想不管怎样修好它让它正常运转
Some people would think for what it's worth to fix it and make the shit work right,
你也可以丢了买台新的
you might as well dump them and get another.
2000块和免费载你去北方 换你的店和库存
2,000 and a free ride north for the store and its contents.
我的店可值更多 Joe
Store worth way more, Joe.
那要看情况了 不是吗
It depends, don't it?
不 该放另一边
No, it goes on the other side and shit.
别他妈朝着我了 我想做点别的
Stop fucking fronting me. I want to do something.
你再骂我 我就砍你
You gonna curse at me again, I'm gonna cut you.
- 把那东西从我面前拿开 - 我不想再弄这个了
- Get that shit out my face. - I don't even want to do this shit no more.
你总是这么干
That's how you always do it.
你干嘛呢 看那盒子
What are you doing? Look at the box.
- 那像盒子上面的吗 - 我做不来
- Do that look like that's on the box? - I can't do this.
伙计 拜托 我想弄坏它
Nigger, come on, now. I'm trying to eat.
- 把那块给我 - 去你的
- Give me that piece, yo. - Fuck you, yo,
你根本不知道该怎么做
because you don't even know what you're doing.
坐好闭上嘴 你懂个屁
Just sit there and shut up because you just don't know.
来啊 让我闭嘴啊
Come over here and make me shut up, then.
你开始惹恼我了 你不知道自己在干什么
- Yo, you starting to piss me off 'cause you don't know what you're doing.
- 你太蠢了 - Z 你做上面 我做中间
- You're too stupid. - Hey, Z, you do the top while I do the middle.
Darnell 你做下面 行吗
Darnell, you got the leg parts, all right?
对 就这样 就这样
Yeah yeah. Like that. Like that.
靠
Shit!
完工
Done.
放屁
Aw, that's bullshit.
他作弊
He's cheating, yo.
你碰碰看啊 宝贝
Go ahead and touch it, baby.
这东西永垂不朽
That shit built to last.
剩下的几块呢
What about the extra pieces?
什么剩下的几块
What extra pieces?
你口袋里是什么
What's in your pocket?
我口袋里没东西
Ain't nothing in my pocket.
这附近哪儿的牛排好吃
So, uh, who cook a good steak around here?
好 第一 从我就职典礼那天开始
Okay. One-- From the day of my inauguration,
Burrell局长将不承担任何实权 凡事需要征得你同意
Commissioner Burrell is to undertake no initiative without clearing it with you.
日常管理职责都归副局长办公室
Day-to-day administrative responsibilities are to reside with the deputy office
不管之前是不是
if they don't already.
我喜欢 没问题
I like that. No problem.
- 第二 我要升Stan Valchek的职 - 好人啊 Valchek
- Two-- I need to elevate Stan Valchek. - Good man, Valchek.
他是个老油条 但他是我的老油条 再说我欠他的
He's a hack, but he's my hack, and I owe him.
如果我任命他为行政代理 会出大问题吗
If I make him Deputy for Admin, can he cause any real damage?
我会看着他的 没问题
I'll watch over him. No problem.
第三 提拔西区警长Daniels为副总警监
Three-- I'm bumping Daniels from Western Command to colonel,
让他管理刑事侦缉部并全权整顿调查单位
giving him ClD and carte blanche to fix the investigative units.
- Cedric Daniels? - 有问题吗
- Cedric Daniels? - Problem?
没有 他是个好警察
No, he's good police.
只是他...
He's just got...
难以驾驭
a little independent streak.
谁难以驾驭
Independent from who:
提拔Daniels我没意见
I got no problem making Daniels.
- 还有什么要求 - 目前就这些了
- What else do you need? - That's it for now.
市长先生 至于Ervin...
Mr. Mayor, about Ervin--
如果你不介意我打听的话
if you don't mind my asking,
你能炒了他 为什么还留着他当傀儡局长
why keep him as a puppet commissioner when you can just fire the guy?
我们介意你打听
We mind you asking.
我偏爱樱桃口味的
I'm partial to them cherries.
- Dukie - 嗯
- Yo, Dukie. - Hmm:
你妈给社会服务机构打过电话吗
You ever call Social Services on your mother?
什么
What?
不知道 我只是想搞清楚
I don't know. I just want to know what happens
给社会服务机构打电话 举报某人会怎么样
if you call Social Services on somebody.
你想举报你妈妈?
You want to report your mother?
她带了某人回家 结果他赖着不走
She brung someone home and he won't leave.
你不会想打电话给社会服务机构的
You don't want to call Social Services.
他们跑来查来查去
They get to looking into things,
把你丢给儿童之家
they could put you in a group home,
甚至让你和Bug兄弟分离
split you and Bug up, even.
我不想让我们分开 只想让他离开
But I don't want us to leave. I just want him to leave.
你是在说Bug的父亲 对吧
Talking about Bug's daddy, ain't you?
也许你该找个老师谈谈
Maybe you ought to talk to a teacher about this.
我是说 Pryzbo先生很有一套
I mean, Mr. Pryzbo is real good about stuff.
P先生说我可以跟学校社工谈谈
Mr. P did say I could go talk to the school social worker.
Roderneck先生? 他是个酒鬼
-Mr. Roderneck? He an alcoholic.
那个打拳击的怎样 Cutty先生?
Oh, um, what about that boxing guy, Mr. Cutty?
Cutty有什么不好吗
What's wrong with Cutty?
不知道
I don't know.
就觉得他过于友好了 懂吗
Like, he just too friendly, you know?
有点吓着我了 伙计
That shit creep me out, man.
他就像个同性恋什么的
Like, he some type of faggot or something.
不 Cutty才不是 伙计 他喜欢女人
Nah, not Cutty, man. He be all up in the women.
你没看他是怎么做的吗
Yo, don't you see how he be doing?
那不能代表什么 同性恋也都这样
That don't mean shit. Them faggots will be just like that, too.
我不知道 他就是友好过头了
And I don't know. He just too friendly, you know?
大家都他妈友好过头了
Everybody just too motherfucking friendly.
不会吧
No fucking way.
他名字叫... 你们叫他什么来着
So, his name is-- what'd you call him?
算是个讽刺吧
It's like a joke.
他们觉得好玩吧
Yeah. They flipped it.
- 一票小丑 - 嗯哼
- Bunch of fucking clowns. - Mm-hmm.
去年我们接受马里兰教学评估测试率 为百分之二十二
Last year we had MSAs in the 22 percentile.
校长在此处暗示巴尔的摩市学校总部
别以为"迷宫"那票人没注意到
And don't think they haven't noticed it down at the Puzzle Palace.
他们号称今年在全市所有中学里
The word is they're looking for at least a 10-point increase
寻求十个百分点的增长
from all city middle schools this time around.
我们离马里兰教学评估测试还有六周
We're still six weeks away from the MSAs
你希望我们现在开始教授那门测试?
and you want us to start teaching the test now?
今年 应该称之为...
This year, the preferred term...
"课程调校"
is "Curriculum Alignment."
着重教导马里兰教学评估测试 所需的技能并没有错
There's nothing wrong with emphasizing the skills necessary for the MSA.
如果要让他们写出段不带脏字的话
If we can get them to write a paragraph without a four-letter word in it,
他们需要更好地掌握英语
it'll have to have better command of English.
Marcia 技能教授是一回事
Marcia, skill sets are one thing,
但这是让我们直接教测试题
but this has us teaching test questions direct,
测试题包括了技能教授
test questions that involve skills.
- 我不懂你想说什么 - 你不会想知道的
- I don't see your point. - You don't want to see the point.
你们期待见到些跟去年不一样的东西吗
Were you really expecting something different than last year?
我没见到数学部分 这些都是语文题
I don't see the math section. These are all language arts questions.
这是我们去年在标准测试中最大的败笔
Our greatest failing on standardized tests last year.
所以目前 所有教师在课上...
So, for the time being, all teachers will devote class time...
都要教授语文样题
to teaching language arts sample questions.
请各位翻到11页
Now, if you turn to page 11, please,
有些内容想和大家过一遍
I have some things I want to go over with you.
我不明白
I don't get it.
这些都为了让我们在州测试中拿高分?
All this so we score higher on the state tests?
如果我们把测试题教给孩子们
If we're teaching the kids the test questions,
- 那是要评估他们什么呢 - 什么都不是 是评估我们
- what is it assessing in them? - Nothing. It assesses us.
测试分数上去了 他们就会说学校改善了
The test scores go up, they can say the schools are improving.
分数上不去 他们就不能这么说
The scores stay down, they can't.
- 伪造数据 - 什么
- Juking the stats. - Excuse me?
把抢劫算成盗窃
Making robberies into larcenies,
隐瞒强奸
making rapes disappear--
伪造数据 警长就能升警监了
you juke the stats and majors become colonels.
我以前在警局待过
I've been here before.
无论上哪
Wherever you go,
都逃不掉
there you are.
Raven有个哥们叫Mike Anderson
Raven's got that dude Mike Anderson.
- 他和Jamal要跑... - 看看这些小鬼
- He and Jamal gonna be running... - Look at these runts.
我们在他们长传的时候出去
We're gonna go when that football's in the air on a long pass.
- 慢慢开? - 对
- Slow? - Yeah.
这有大黄
Big yellow right here.
- 黄盖 黄盖 - 远点 远点
- Yellows, yellows! - Go long. Go go.
- 扔高点 - 大黄
- Throw it high. - Big yellow.
快
Go.
- 缉毒警 - 靠
- Narco! - Oh, shit!
条子 条子
Po-po, yo! Po-po!
- 往哪跑 - 放我下来 贱人 - 他们在巷子里
- Where you going? - Put me down, bitch! - They're in the alleys.
我们回去 能逮住他们
We get back in there, we can hunt them up.
没必要 我都认识
- No need. I know 'em all.
- 放开我 混蛋 - 这个怎么办
- Let me go, motherfucker! - What about this one?
他连饵都算不上 放他走
He isn't even bait. We toss him back--
除非你想剩下半天班都看孩子
unless you want to spend half the shift down at baby booking.
- 我呢 - 我不怕你 混球
- Me: - I ain't afraid, motherfucker!
我可不想半天班花在证物科那
I don't want to spend this shift down at Evidence Control.
- 那你抓他们干嘛 - 这样我就能跟他们谈谈了
- Then why the fuck even do this? - So's I can talk to them.
在手铐大小合适前 我觉得这样比较好
I like to think that until the handcuffs actually fit,
- 该跟他们谈谈 - 放开我
- there's  still talking to be done.- Let me go.
过来 伙计 我们走走
Come here, man. Let's take a walk.
你他妈闭嘴
You shut the fuck up.
这是谁的歌
Yo, who we listening to?
Lady Day小姐 Billie Holliday (前为昵称 美国歌手)
Miss Lady Day, Billie Holliday.
听着不错
Yeah, she sounds good.
有点悲伤的感觉
You know, real sad, kind of.
嗯 我喜欢
Yeah. I'm like that.
你会以为我是贱民
You be thinking I'm all ghetto,
接着我还击 让你脑袋一团浆糊
and then I flip it and mess your mind all up.
下次出来 Colvin先生
The next time we do this, Mr. Colvin,
能选在周末吗
could you please make it on the weekend?
我放学后大概就三小时做准备
I only had, like, three hours between school and now to get ready.
- 你看起来不错 Zenobia - 可以更好的
- Well, you look fine, Zenobia. - I could look better.
你以为做这个头要多长时间
How long you think it take to do hair like this?
我预定了最大的巨无霸 还有炸薯条
I'm ordering the biggest quarter-pounder. Fries, too.
小子 这里可不是麦当劳
Nigger, this ain't Mickey D's.
你该想的是带骨牛排 生熟适中
You better be thinking T-bone steak, medium rare.
- 血会喷出来那种? - 没血的
- The blood all squirting out? - Nah, ain't no blood.
你以为略生是怎样 就是基本不煮?
What you think rare is? It mean rarely cooked, hardly cooked?
- 略生 有血 笨蛋 - 听见没
- Rare. Get the blood out, stupid. - See?
生熟适中 血就不出来了
And medium rare, keep the blood in.
好吧 听着
All right. Look.
我点未处理的肉前得先搞清楚哪种是哪种
All I want to know which is which before I order some undone meat.
- 嘿 Colvin先生 - 嗯?
- Hey, Mr. Colvin. - Huh?
- 是怎样的 - 听着 我们去那问服务生就好了 行吗
- How it work: - Look, we're just gonna ask the waiter. All right?
靠 还有服务生?
Oh, shit. There's a waiter?
就在街尾
Just right down the block.
- 她在哪 小子 - 没见过
- Where she at, dawg? - Ain't seen her.
她欠我 我给了她那么多
She owe me. All that shit I gave her.
了解 我不知道
Yeah, I know. I don't know.
- 你怎么会不知道的 - 我不知道
- How you not know? - I don't know.
让我找到 我要把她咪咪都切了
She let me find her, I'm gonna cut her titty off.
看着吧
Watch.
- 你有什么要说吗 小子 - 没有
- You got something to say, nigger? - No no.
Herc在哪
Yo, where Herc at?
我找到那混蛋了
I got the asshole, okay?
告诉他Riggs和Calhoun街角
Tell him Riggs and Calhoun.
他知道的 他知道的
He knows. He knows.
好的
Okay.
他妈的过来
Get the fuck back here.
小子 我操你
Nigger, I will fuck you up.
你不认识Lex?
You don't know Lex?
我以前认识那家伙
I knew the Bull.
我是说 我曾认识他
I mean, I know him.
但他很久没出现了
But he ain't been around though.
看见没 就刚才 你露陷了
You see? Right there. You just fucked up.
你说你"曾认识"他 就好像你知道他死了
You said you "knew" him, like you knew he was dead.
不 你这是硬套我话了
No. Now you putting words in my mouth.
我是说 "认识他"
I meant, "knew him."
他以前在这出现 我认识他 但他离开了
When he was around, I knew him. But he left.
Herc
Herc.
Bubbles来过电话 他看见了那个混蛋
Bubbles called. He sees the guy--the asshole.
他在Riggs和Calhoun街角
He's on Riggs and Calhoun.
他说他会在那等你五分钟过去
Says he'll hold him there five minutes for you to get across town.
我这边在审讯呢 什么玩意
I'm in the middle of an interview here. What the fuck?
告诉他 我们明天帮他搞定
Tell him we'll fix his problem tomorrow.
行吗
All right?
混球
Oh, motherfucker.
他没电话
He ain't got a phone.
你在街上对我撒谎了 我为什么要信你
You lied to me out on the street. Why should l believe you now?
Lex被杀时你在场 你也参与了设计他
You was there when Lex got killed. You part of the fucking setup.
我们知道 因为我们有证人证明你在场
We know 'cause we have a witness who put you right in there.
没错 我们知道尸体在哪
Yeah, we do. You know right where that body is.
你跟Snoop
You were there with Snoop,
Chris 还有别的什么人在场
Chris, whoever else.
知道该怎么审讯吗
Know how to make an interrogation work?
要有料
Leverage.
我们手上没有砝码?
We don't have leverage?
操蛋家伙 你们连尸体都没有
Motherfucker, you don't even got a body.
Lex就是个黑板上的名字
Lex is nothing but a name in there.
你他妈想上哪去
Where the fuck you think you're going?
你哪也别想去
You ain't going nowhere.
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hello!
家庭仓库 家庭仓库
Home Depot here! Home Depot!
今晚有什么要孝敬我的
What you got for me tonight?
我一整天没见着你了 伙计
I've been missing you all day long, dawg.
不 我们就在这了结了吧 了结了
No no. We done with this right here. We done with this.
你说什么 别玩了 伙计 我没时间陪你玩
Say what? Don't play, man. I ain't got time for your shit.
你吃屎吧
My shit's all you're gonna get, all right?
亲我屁股吧 你找了我那么多麻烦
You can kiss my ass, all the fucking trouble you given me.
你找什么
What you looking for, huh?
那儿没有 都在我身上
It's not there. It's on me, all right?
- 在你身上? - 对
- It's on you? - Yeah.
- 在你身上? - 等等 等等
- It's on you? - Wait wait wait!
不 不 不
Oh, no no no!
放开我! 放开我!
Get off me! Get off me!
不要! 滚开!
Come on! Get off!
等等 等等
Hey, wait wait wait!
你拿去! 拿去!
You take it! Take it!
- 抓到你了 - 不 不 不
- I got you now! - No no no!
操!
Fuck!
我不喜欢橙色的
I don't like the orange ones.
听着 混蛋 我们知道你在场
Listen to me, fuckhead. We know you were there.
我们知道你设计了他
We know you set him up,
我们也知道你不是一个人干的
and we know you didn't do it alone.
说什么
Say what?
你不是一个人干的 我们知道
You weren't alone in this. We know that.
你是说Randy?
You mean Randy?
问问题的是我 懂吗
I'm asking you questions, remember?
如果你不交代这桩谋杀 Kevin
If you don't give us this murder, Kevin,
会有人交代的 到时候
somebody else will. And when they do,
你就得进监狱了 听见了吗
they'll be putting you in. You hear me?
Colvin 四人
Colvin, party of four.
我去准备好你的桌子
I'll make sure your table's ready.
"Colvin 四人"?
"Colvin, party of four," huh?
要我帮你拿大衣吗
Hi. May I take your coat?
好的
Sure.
- 你呢 先生? - 不 不用了
- You, sir? - Oh, no. I'm good.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
你的桌子准备好了
Okay, your table's ready.
请跟我来
Follow me, please.
- 先生? - 那是你的座位 对吧
- Sir? - That's your chair, right?
不 你坐那
No. You sit there.
侍应生很快过来介绍今天的特供餐
The waitress will be here soon to detail the specials of the day.
- 慢用 - 谢谢
- Enjoy. - Thank you.
侍应生? 是什么
Waitress? Who was that?
是女引位
That's the, uh, hostess.
你用不着担心 C先生
Hey, you ain't gotta worry, Mr. C.
我不会让你破费的
I ain't gonna run up your bill.
无论特别供应的是什么 我就点那个了
I'll just get whatever's on special.
这不是超市的特价商品 蠢货
It ain't no K-Mart Blue Light Special, dumbass.
特别供应是说他们的烹调与众不同
Special just mean they cook something different.
那你呢 不用吸管喝水 一副贫民样?
Yo, what about you, drinking without a straw, all ghetto and shit?
喝水不用吸管的
You don't drink water with a straw.
那个放膝盖上 笨蛋
And put that on your lap, fool.
你看这里还有谁一副Fred Flintstone样吗 (动画角色 带着蓝色领巾)
You see anybody else up in here Iooking all Fred Flintstone and shit?
嘘
Shh.
小声点 别人都盯着我们呢
Shut it down. Other people be looking at us.
你好 我叫Pam
Hello. My name is Pam.
我向你们推荐今天的特色菜
I'd like to tell you about our specials for the day.
我们有国王鲑鱼配甜玉米
We have king salmon with sweet corn,
鸡油菌配罗勒色拉酱
chanterelles and basil aioli;
嫩煎放养鸡与土豆泥
sauteed free-range chicken served with mashed potatoes;
鲜Chesapeake湾蓝蟹 烤大蒜 葱香奶油
fresh Chesapeake Bay blue crab, roasted garlic, shallot cream
还有舞茸
and hen-of-the-woods mushrooms;
木箱烤鹌鹑配烤面包沙拉
and wood-oven-roasted quail with grilled bread salad.
靠 我还以为你们只有牛排呢
Dang, I thought y'all had steak.
有... 在你菜单上的第二页
Oh, we do...on the second page of your menus.
你们要什么喝的吗
May I get your drink orders?
来四杯可乐吧
Yeah. We'll take four cokes, please.
- 马上来 - 谢谢
- Right away. - Thank you.
你介意我明天过来吗
Do you mind if I come tomorrow?
介意?
Mind:
我...
I--
你不会尴尬吗
You wouldn't be embarrassed?
不 完全不会
No, not at all.
我是说...
I mean...
如果你在那 我会很自豪
I'll be proud if you're there.
这结果很可笑
It's funny how it works out.
这么多年来我想方设法往上爬
All those years I'm trying to climb the ladder,
拍马屁 替人擦屁股 任人使唤
kissing ass, covering ass, doing what I'm told.
我终于爆发了 说出我真实想法了
I finally let some of it out, tell 'em what I really think,
却从警督升到了副总警监 才一年多一点
and I'm going from lieutenant to colonel in a little more than a year.
还有你 你对那些传票担心得不得了
And, you, you're worried sick about those subpoenas
还担心Lester会毁了你和你上司...
and worried that Lester's killing you with your boss--
但这些传票让我晋升了
But the subpoenas get me promoted.
我知道
I know.
知道吗 Marlo曾对我说过
You know, Marlo once said to me,
"你不玩就不会输"
"You cannot lose if you do not play."
但我们现在就这样了 对吧
But here we are, right?
也许正在改变
Maybe it's changing.
什么
What is?
城市 那些事情成与不成的方式
The city, the way things work or don't.
也许我们到了一个
Maybe we're turning a corner here
再没那么难以置信地操蛋的点
and it's not gonna be so unbelievably fucked up anymore.
敬Carcetti
To Carcetti.
还有我们
And us.
Zenobia
Zenobia,
你想给餐厅照张相 对吧
you want to take a picture of the restaurant, right?
无所谓 太晚了
That's okay. It's late.
不 没事的 来吧 相机给我
No no. That's fine. Come on. Give me the camera.
- 我没关系 - 来吧 给我相机
- I'm okay. - Come on, give me the camera.
好啦
Okay.
你们都想被拍进去吧
Y'all want to be in the picture, right?
C先生 我们能在麦当劳前停一下吗
Yo, Mr. C, can we stop at McDonald's?
- 你什么毛病 小子 - 不好吃
- Fuck wrong with you, boy? - Food wasn't right.
我不喜欢鱼
Don't like fish.
那你干嘛要点
Why'd you order it, then?
闭嘴
Yo, shut the fuck up.
- 关小点 - 什么
- Turn it down. - What?
关小点 Namond
Turn it down, Namond.
开大声点? 行 没问题
Turn it up? All right, you got it.
说真的 至少让我们来点薯条吧
Seriously, can we get some fries at least?
小子 你真可悲
Boy, you is pathetic.
别以为你是女的我就不打你
Just 'cause you a girl do not mean I won't fuck you all up.
- 听见没 - 小子 拜托
- You hear me? - Nigger, please.
- 你老说些有的没的 - 不 你老说些有的没的
- Yeah, you keep talking all of that shit. - No, you keep talking all that shit.
- 你一定是忘了 - 不 我从不忘事
- Must have forgot. - No, I ain't forget shit.
- 我忘了什么 - 忘了我是个男的
- What I forget anyway? - That I'm the man.
好吧
Okay.
当我们回应一个提示时
So, what's the first thing we do
首先该怎么做
when we respond to a prompt?
Randy?
"根据上下文..."?
"According to the text..."?
"根据上下文"
"According to the text."
很好
That's good.
我们以什么结束呢
And how do we end the answer?
- Quenice? - 嗯?
- Quenice? - Huh?
说吧 你知道的
Come on. I know you know this.
"根据上述事实 我认为..."
"The above-stated facts have led me to conclude that..."
对吧
Right?
好吧 我们读一下第三段
Okay. So, let's try to read the third paragraph.
我来开头
I'll start it.
"Pythias最后一次恳求暴君Dionysius..." (即古罗马刎颈之交的典故)
"Pythias makes a final plea to the tyrant Dionysius...
"让他最后回一次家..."
to return to his home one last--"
Calvin 接下去
Calvin, pick it up.
"让他受刑前最后回一次家"
"To return to his home one last time before his punishment.
"他拒绝了这一请求 直到Damon说..."
He denies the request until Damon inter..."
"说项"
"lntercedes."
"...并用他性命担保Pythias会回来"
"...and offers his own life until Pythias returns."
很好
Good.
谁来猜猜"说项"是什么意思
Who wants to guess what "intercedes" means?
那"恳求"呢
What about "plea"?
好吧 那这个故事呢
Okay. What about the story, then?
你们能怎么概括
How would you summarize it?
Duquan 试试
Duquan, give it a shot.
"根据上下文..."
"According to the text..."
大家最后都没事了?
everybody's safe in the end, right?
好吧 我们这样想
Okay. Let's think this through.
"根据上下文"
"According to the text,
Damon用他的生命为Pythias担保
Damon offers his own life on behalf of Pythias
"好让他最后回一次家"
so that he can return home one last time.
"由上述事实我们知道"
The above-stated facts have led me to conclude
"Damon重视与Pythias的友谊与忠贞"
that Damon values Pythias' friendship and loyalty."
有问题吗
Any questions?
我们要四份生货
We want four of the raw.
这里有27万5千块
275 large right there.
四份该是30万
For four it should be three.
纽约人的人头 我要价是5千一个 这算是我的工资吧
I'm charging five a head on them New York boys. That about the going rate.
还要我们继续看着吗
Still want us on that?
不 看样子他们收到我们的讯息滚蛋了
Nah, seems like they got the message and went the fuck on.
那倒是
True that.
Delroy收回了所有Monument街的街角
Delroy has all of the Monument Street corners back.
那好 货来了通知我们
All right, then. Holler at us when the next package in.
你记得我跟你说的合作社的含义吧
Uh, you remember when I told you about the co-op meant
我们站在同一阵线
we all stand together,
有能力时互相帮助 记得吗
doing for each other when we can? You remember that?
四份生货的要价是30万
Well, the price of four raw is 300.
你对付纽约帮的事已经算进价格中了
And your work on them New York boys already been factored into the price, you see?
另一方面 我们有你想要的 就回馈给你...
On the other hand,we got something that you want, and it's coming back to you...
免费
free of charge.
你找的某人
Someone you looking for.
合作社顾名思义 伙计
Co-op mean what it sound like, dawg.
你助我为乐 我助你为乐
You happy to do for me, I'm happy to do for you.
恭喜 副总警监
Congratulations, Colonel.
恭喜 副局长
Congratulations, Deputy Commissioner.
恭喜晋升的诸位 他们的家人和朋友
Congratulations to all those who were promoted, their families, and friends.
这是他们值得骄傲的一天
It's a proud day for them
也是巴尔的摩警局值得骄傲的一天
and a proud day for the Baltimore Police Department.
- 我真为你骄傲 - 谢谢
- I am so proud of you. - Oh, thank you.
你知道 Valchek还猜得到
You know, Valchek we could have guessed.
他毕竟是Carcetti的人 但...
I mean, he's Carcetti's man, but...
Daniels?
你当上警长花了挺长时间 但这次可够快了
Long time for you to make major, but this was quick enough.
就是 你请了谁当你新法师啊
Yeah, who's your new rabbi, huh?
副总警监
Colonel.
他们分不清色拉叉
So, they didn't know the salad fork
和其他用来这样那样的叉子 又怎样
from whatever the fuck the other fork is for. So what?
我知道他们会困惑 但其程度...
I knew they'd be at a loss, but the extent of it...
我说的是感受
I'm talking about feelings--
他们有这感受的原因...
why they feeling this...
这种从无所不知到恐惧
this plummet from masters of the universe to abject fear
到蒙羞狂怒的落差 他们却不自知
to humiliated fury and no awareness of it.
谁说他们不知道
Who says they're not aware?
也许他们只是不承认
Maybe they just didn't acknowledge.
不管怎样 我的意思是 你对他们从哪开始?
Either way. But my point is, where do you start with them?
你怎样让他们相信自己
How you get them to believe in themselves
如果他们连承认他们对自己在这世上
if they can't even admit their feelings about who they are
扮演什么角色的感觉都做不到的话?
and what they're doing in this world?
他们不是笨蛋
They're not fools.
他们知道我们对他们的期望
They know exactly what we expect them to be.
你们想真正的晚餐了吧
Y'all missed some meal for real, though.
- 请坐 - 那地方不错
- Take your seats. - It was hot, yo.
"四位 Colvin先生"
"Party of four, Mr. Colvin."
"要我替你拿大衣吗 Brice先生?"
"May I take your coat, Mr. Brice?"
说得真时髦
Ha! That shit was tight.
我梦想吃巧克力蛋糕
I'm dreaming about that chocolate cake.
老天
Oh my God.
那个大概有56层
Shit had, like, 56 layers, yo!
"...在衣帽间 Colvin先生...
"...in the check-room, Mr. Colvin...
"玩音乐的救了矿工"?
"D Money saves Pitman"?
搞什么啊
It's bullshit!
在这之前 他们本来开始有点用心了
Before, at least they were getting something out of it.
去他的评估 去他的Donnelly
To hell with my evaluation. To hell with Donnelly,
去他的州测验分数
to hell with the statewide test scores.
我是来教书的
I came here to teach.
对吧
Right?
教练 有见到Michael吗
Yo, Coach, seen Michael?
没有
Nah.
好吧
All right.
那昨天我见到在Bentlow贩毒的 就不是你和你的小崽子了?
That wasn't you and your runts I saw down on Bentlow yesterday, slinging?
对
Right.
因为想你这样的帮派分子 不会建立一个这么废的店
'Cause a gangster like yourself wouldn't set up such a weak-ass shop
没有真正望风的 藏毒点一目了然
with no real lookouts, ground stash in plain view.
我跟你说得明明白白的
This is me telling y'all as plain as I can.
我给了你们一次机会
You guys had your one chance.
下次再让我看见你们
I see you out there a second time,
都揍一顿扔到Cheltenham (少管所所在地)
everyone takes a beating and goes to Cheltenham.
给你们警告了
Fair warning you just got.
贩毒去Cheltenham?
Cheltenham for some drug charges?
拜托 伙计
Please, man.
我会给你特别照顾的
I'll write you up as a special.
别以为我不会这么做
Don't think I won't do it.
打 打 很好
Jab, jab! Good.
他觉得我进不了监狱?
He don't think I can jail?
靠 我也能进监狱...
Shit! I can jail...
- 怎么样 - Namond在外面混?
- What's up? - Namond's banging, huh?
对 他是你徒弟 对吧
Yeah. He's one of yours, right?
他在健身房出没
He hang around the gym,
多是等他朋友Michael
mostly waiting on his boy Michael.
他不打拳
He don't box or nothing.
他不是那个料 真的 不像他爸
He ain't that kind, really. Not like his father.
- 他爸是谁? - 一个叫Wee-Bey的哥们
- Who was his father? - Dude named Wee-Bey.
硬汉 以前跟Barksdale一伙混
Stone-headed. Used to run with them Barksdales.
我知道他
I know him.
靠 是我在费城抓了他
Shit, I locked him up in Philadelphia.
是吗
Yeah?
Bey是我狱友
Bey was my cut buddy.
我们一起在Jessup坐牢
We jailed down Jessup.
无论如何 Namond是他生的
Anyway, Namond's from him.
血脉相连 但虎父犬子
Same blood, but not the same heart.
我热身完了 教练
I've done my warm-ups, Coach.
我们准备好了
Yeah. We ready for the ring!
保重 伙计
Take care, man.
停这干嘛 还以为我们要开出去呢
Why we stopping here? I thought we was going straight out.
等把你送出去的人
Gotta get with your escort out.
Prop Joe说是你送我出去
Prop Joe said you was my escort out.
从某个角度说 没错
Manner of speaking, that be true.
过来 伙计
Come on over here, man.
过来
Come on.
老天 不要
Chris, no.
你知道我会很快结束的 Dre
You know I keep it quick, Dre.
- 在这? - 这里不错
- Here? - Here's good.
- 别 别在个空巷子里 - 有什么区别
- Not-- not in a vacant. - What's the difference?
区别在我的人不会知道
The difference is my people. They won't know.
他们会知道的
They'll know.
但 但 但有老鼠
But-- but-- but the rats.
- 我会单独跟老鼠待在一起 - 没事的
- I'll be alone with the rats. - You're all right.
我们挺你
I got your back.
拜托 老天 让我在我家了断 这样我的人...
Come on, Chris. Let me do it in my house so my people--
他们可以送我一程
they can give me a home go.
该死
I'll be damned.
谁
Que?
那绝对是Marlo 伙计
Hey, yo, that got to be Marlo, man.
看见没
You see?
是我们抢那个人
That's the man we robbed, yo,
在牌局上
from the poker game.
是哦 是哦
si, si, si.
难怪那小子不喜欢我
No wonder the boy don't like me.
还以为我会跟Chris聊聊
Thought maybe I could catch up with Chris.
我有个麻烦 没法跟别人说
I got a problem I can't bring to no one else.
那是谁
Quien es?
只是个小鬼
He just a kid.